hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation playlist now
continuing with our obstacles topic
let's look at our next obstacle which is
called and Counting so in this we have
got a autocomplete text box so when we
type this particular text which is DDD
here right you can see that uh it
contains a list of different text right
so as you uh keep typing it will search
and find out all the similar uh text uh
in this particular list right so uh we
need to count the entries in this list
and then we need to enter the number of
that particular entries uh in this
particular text box right so for DDD you
can see there are five entries so we
need to enter here five and when you
enter five uh this automation obstacle
will be completed so that's what we need
to automate using tosa Okay so let's go
ahead and do this in tosa now now to
make this a little bit easier I have
already uh scanned this particular
module okay so let's go through what are
the different elements which are present
here so this is the span element okay uh
and it represents this particular text
which we have to enter okay so it is a
span element and we will use the inner
text to basically grab this text right
and then we have got uh this text box we
have got this text box and then we have
also got a list here right so that's uh
the elements we have scanned uh you can
see this is the autocomplete text box
then this is the list okay so you can
see the list uh item here and this is
the underlying
list and then uh we have got the text
box which is the entry count right now
if I go ahead and look at the properties
uh one of the things which you need to
take care is the title uh that may be
dynamic so always try to use regular
expressions in your title okay and then
uh coming to the list item now uh we
have already seen and talked about
cardinality so since uh these you can
see there are lots of different items
here right and uh we are not going to
scan each and every item in this list
right so uh we can scan just one element
type and then we can use the cardinality
0 to n right so we have increased the
cardinality here because we want to
count all the elements in that
particular list right so uh yeah so
that's that's all you need to do in the
in your module attributes and then let's
go ahead and create a new test case here
now okay so I'm going to rename this to
uh this particular obstacle
number okay and then then uh I'm going
to drag this module right here okay now
uh this span as I said we will be taking
the inner text value which is contains
the actual text right for that uh we
will choose your inner text and here we
will see or give uh text as the value
and what we'll do we'll change the
action mode to buffer so what it will do
it will uh grab the inner text and then
it will store it in this text value
okay and then uh coming to this autoc
complete so here we need to uh type the
text right and although you can directly
enter the text uh that won't work out
because uh it's a autocomplete text box
so in this case you can use the send
keys right so what it will do it will
send one key from the keyboard into that
particular text box
right so uh here uh we have to use the
buffer which we have stored earlier so
we'll we use a buffer of text here
okay and this will be our input right
now uh coming to the list item here what
we'll do is we'll use another property
of a list through which we can count the
number of items and that is called the
result count
okay so here we can type the result
count property
and here we can again buffer this to a
particular buffer value okay I will
change the action mode to buffer so the
result count of this particular list
will be stored in this count
right and once we get the count then we
can directly enter it uh with the buffer
so buffer of
count
right so couple of things uh we have
seen uh we have to use the send Keys
instead of uh directly inputting the
text here because uh it's a autocomplete
text box so we have to enter Keys one by
one right then we are buffering uh the
inner text uh from the span element
which becomes our text and then we are
using the result count property for the
list uh items so that we can uh get the
count of all the items right and then we
are storing it in a buffer and then we
are entering that uh account value into
the text box right so let's go ahead and
execute this
now so as you can see it uh entered the
text which is CCC and then um it counted
how many uh C CC are present in that
particular list and then it entered two
which is the number of uh text which is
present in the count here right and then
this particular op CLE was
completed so this is how you can use
different concepts to basically solve uh
your automation problem right so you can
use the action mode buffer you can use
some properties like the inner text the
result count uh to get the count of uh
the list of items and then you can also
use the send keys to enter some keys
into a autocomplete text
box that's all for this particular video
if you have any questions then please
leave it in the comments if you like
this video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next
video